A legacy worth killing for.
House of Gucci is a drama, crime, history film directed by Ridley Scott.
When Patrizia Reggiani, an outsider from humble beginnings, marries into the Gucci family, her unbridled ambition begins to
unravel the family legacy and triggers a reckless spiral of betrayal, decadence, revenge, and ultimately… murder.
Patrizia Reggiani, played by Lady Gaga.
Maurizio Gucci, played by Adam Driver.
Aldo Gucci, played by Al Pacino.
Rodolfo Gucci, played by Jeremy Irons.
Paolo Gucci, played by Jared Leto.
Domenico De Sole, played by Jack Huston.
House of Gucci is a 2021 American biographical crime drama film directed by Ridley Scott, based on the 2001 book
The House of Gucci: A Sensational Story of Murder, Madness, Glamour, and Greed by Sara Gay Forden.
The film follows Patrizia Reggiani (Lady Gaga) and Maurizio Gucci (Adam Driver) as their
romance transforms into a fight for control of the Italian fashion brand Gucci.
Jared Leto, Jeremy Irons, Jack Huston, Salma Hayek and Al Pacino also star.
Scott wanted to make a film about the Gucci dynasty after
acquiring rights to Forden's book in the early 2000s.
The project languished for several years, with several directors and actors rumored to be
considered before Scott and Gaga became officially attached in November 2019.
Much of the remaining cast joined the following summer, and filming
began in Italy, lasting from February through May 2021.
The world premiere of House of Gucci was held at the Odeon Luxe
Leicester Square in London on November 9, 2021.
It was theatrically released in the United States on November 24, 2021.
The film received mixed reviews from critics, who praised the cast's
performances but criticized the inconsistent tone and editing.
Gaga and Leto were nominated for the Screen Actors Guild Award, Critics' Choice Award, and Satellite Award for Best Actress and
Best Supporting Actor, respectively, while Gaga also received nominations for the Golden Globe Award and BAFTA Award.
The film also earned a nomination at the 94th Academy
Awards for Best Makeup and Hairstyling.
It grossed more than $153 million against a $75 million budget.
The film explores themes of marriage crisis, italy,
biography, fashion designer, murder.
The tone is emotional.